carleton.ca 2005-12-10

# ACCESS TO INFORMATION

**

V. PROTECTION OF PRIVACY

**

**1.** Except where specific agreements have been reached in collective bargaining, the regulations below shall govern the collection, use, disclosure, retention and disposal, access and correction rights, and exemption from the access right of personal or private information.

**2.** The University shall collect and record only such personal information as is either reasonably necessary to the proper administration of the University and its academic and/or other programs or is required by virtue of data collection or reporting requirements lawfully imposed upon the University by the authority of the federal or provincial government.

**3 _._** The University shall not use personal information in its custody or under its control except:

**(a)** where the person to whom the information relates has identified that information in particular and has consented to its use;

**(b)** for the purpose for which it was obtained or compiled or for a consistent purpose;

**(c)** for statistical analyses; or

**(d)** in other circumstances, where the use of the information is necessary and proper in the discharge of the University's functions and responsibilities.

**4.** The University shall not disclose personal information in its custody or under its control except:

**(a)** under the access to information regulations;

**(b)** where the person to whom the information relates has identified that information in particular and has consented to its disclosure;

**(c)** for the purpose for which it was obtained or compiled or for a consistent purpose;

**(d)** to an officer or employee of the University who needs the record in the performance of his or her duty;

**(e)** for the purpose of complying with a requirement to provide information lawfully imposed upon the University by the authority of the provincial or federal government;

**(f)** where disclosure is to an institution or a law enforcement agency in Canada to aid in an investigation undertaken with a view to a law enforcement proceeding or from which a law enforcement proceeding is likely to result;

**(g)** where disclosure is necessary to aid in the investigation of allegations that individuals have made false statements or engaged in other misleading conduct concerning their attendance or performance or status within or completion of an academic program of the University;

**(h)** where disclosure is made to another educational institution or to a professional licensing authority or board of certification or similar institution, provided that the University has made reasonable efforts to inform affected individuals of the existence of a practice of making such disclosures;

**(i)** in compelling circumstances affecting the health or safety of an individual if upon disclosure notification thereof is mailed to the last known address of the individual to whom the information relates;

**(j)** in compassionate circumstances, to facilitate contact with the next of kin or a friend of an individual who is injured, ill or deceased; or

**(k)** to a person who has been authorized by the individual to whom the information relates to make an enquiry on that individual's behalf, or where that **** individual is incapacitated or deceased, has been authorized by the next of kin or legal representative of that individual.

**5.** The restrictions on disclosure set out in this section on Protection of Privacy do not apply to the fact that an individual is or is not employed by the University or is or is not registered in a particular academic unit, program or session or to the fact that an individual has successfully graduated or completed a program on a particular date or has or has not received particular academic or other University honour or distinctions.

**6.** The University shall take reasonable precautions to protect the security of records containing personal information, shall retain such information only for reasonable periods of time and shall make reasonable arrangements for the disposal or destruction of such records when that reasonable period has expired.

**7.** Every individual who is an employee or student of the University shall be granted access to records containing personal information concerning the individual with respect to which the individual is able to provide sufficiently specific information to render the record reasonably retrievable by the University.

**8.** Every individual who is given access under these regulations to information concerning her/himself is entitled to:

**(a)** request correction of the personal information where the individual believes there is an error or omission;

**(b)** require that a statement of disagreement be attached to the information reflecting any correction that was requested but not made.

**9.** The University may refuse to disclose to the individual to whom the information relates personal information:

**(a)** where the information is privileged, private or confidential as defined by these regulations;

**(b)** where disclosure would constitute an unjustified invasion of another individual's personal privacy;

> > **(c)** if it is evaluative or opinion material compiled solely:

> > **(i)** for the purpose of determining suitability, eligibility, or qualification for employment or for the awarding of a contract with the University;

**(ii)** for the purpose of determining eligibility or admission to an academic program of the University;

**(iii)** for the purpose of determining eligibility or suitability for the awarding of a scholarship, bursary or other form of financial assistance, or

**(iv)** for the purpose of peer review processes related to determinations concerning eligibility or suitability for the granting of tenure or promotion, research grants or other benefits to members of the faculty or for similar purposes;

> > > where disclosure could reveal the identity of a source of furnished information in circumstance where it may reasonably have been assumed that the identity of the source would be held in confidence;

**(d)** that is medical information where disclosure could reasonably be expected to prejudice the mental and/or physical health of the individual; or
